The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Ninth Episode
The Broken Idols
Sapphire gave me an
appointment in the castle.
Here is the place he was
talking about! Right below me!
That construction looks
like a gallows. Strange...
What is a gallows doing
in this castle?
And all those people
lined up down there?
What does all this mean?
Has Prince Sapphire
not arrived yet?
- No, I'm not putting it on!
- But you have to put it on!
It's for the ceremony! It's the
costume for the visit to the sacred idols!
- Everyone has one!
- Put it on!
The sacred idols
have always protected us!
- We must thank them!
- Yes, that's right!
If I wear it, will you give me...
...something to eat?
I've been fasting.
I'm sorry, Prince.
So now you will give me
something to eat, I hope.
Of course, immediately! Here it is!
And what would this be?
Stale bread.
Whoever eats it today,
will be blessed and happy
all year long.
Ah, I see
It's tradition that on this day
nothing else is eaten.
The same tradition dictates that
you don't take more than a bite of it.
Well, it's time to get moving.
Your Majesty, we have brought you
His Highness Prince Sapphire.
Where is the Prince? I don't see him.
You're right!
The Prince is gone!
Idiots!
We cannot begin
the ceremony in honor of the sacred
idols without Prince Sapphire,
- so run and look for him!
- I'm coming!
- That sounds like my son's voice.
- Yes, it was Sapphire!
Good morning, beloved parents.
Oh, no! What have you done
with your costume?
Why?
How funny!
Stop laughing!
With that funny outfit,
he looks like a scarecrow!
Sapphire, be polite
and stop laughing!
I'm sorry, Mom.
I couldn't help it.
The program
of today's ceremony...
...includes entering the tower
in which are kept...
...the images
of the ancestors of the idols,
to pay them homage
and clean them of dust!
Are you all ready?
Now we will enter this
sacred place only one at a time.
I'll go in first!
Good heavens, how high it is!
You will climb to the very top, to the place
assigned to each of you,
and you will set yourselves
patiently to work!
And what is this? From its appearance
it looks like it's a doll.
What a funny face it has!
Don't touch it!
Get away from there immediately!
It is sacrilege
to touch the sacred idols!
it is sacrilege to mock
the images! Sacrilege!
Nylon, tell them
to open the windows!
Women, now open the
windows and start cleaning! Clear?
- What is this, father?
- It is the sovereign idol.
The idol that was
erected by our ancestors...
...to keep evil spirits
away from our land!
It's imposing!
Stupid, don't look down
or the height will scare you!
Maybe she has vertigo!
An idol is falling!
Watch out!
The idol will break!
The curse will fall upon us!
Let's get out of here!
Sapphire! It must have been smashed to pieces!
Thank heaven, you are safe! And you
managed to save the idol too!
Fool!
Do you know what punishment is received by
someone who risks breaking an idol?
Yes... Our law says
that whoever drops an idol...
..or causes its face to be broken
will have their face cut.
If they cause an arm or a
leg to be broken, they will have theirs cut off too!
And finally... if they cause the head to be broken,
they will be hanged!
Well said! Even the daughters
of noblemen, like you,
can be punished!
Don't be so harsh!
After all, the idol didn't break!
I don't know how to thank you
for saving the idol.
Now I will put it back in its place.
Give it here!
Here, take it!
Thank goodness...!
All's well that ends well.
You take care of them, Nylon.
- Yes, Sire.
- Who is coming?
It's Tink!
I'm really curious to see
what's in that strange building.
I didn't want to scare you!
Good heavens! The idol is falling!
Oh, no!
Who was it?! Come on, say it!
And don't faint over so little, ugh!
So, who was it?
It was all my fault,
Baron Nylon!
Come on, bring him here!
- Right away, Grand Duke!
- No! No! No!
Please! Let me go! No! No!
Majesty, your seal will
be enough on this Order...
...and we will proceed
immediately to the execution.
My heart breaks
to execute a child,
but even if it's hard,
the law is the law.
- Who is this hothead?
- But it's His Highness!
What do you want to do with Tink!
Do you mean that young rascal
who is to be executed?
- Executed?! - Unfortunately, he has
committed a major crime,
by breaking one of our idols.
Now he must pay with his life.
But that is terrible!
Tink, you
Damn it, get away!
What are you doing, Your Highness? Have you gone mad?
Let go of me!
I must put an end to this
superstition or others will die!
There, now I feel much better.
What? Have they broken other idols?
What a sacrilegious act!
Right! Therefore, Sire,
you must sign...
...for the immediate execution
of the culprit.
You sign for me.
I am sleepy.
As you wish!
It's time for my bed to be prepared
At your command, Majesty
- Duralumin!
- Yes, Sire?
What do you say if we passed a
law to abolish the death penalty?
It is not a good idea, Your Majesty.
Have you considered...
...that if we do not punish those
who break the sacred idols,
the evil spirits
will curse us...
...and fill your kingdom
with misfortune and death?
My goodness! I don't want
such a thing to happen!
That's better! Begin!
I will be hanged from the tower!
But that is my son Sapphire!
Goodbye, dear parents!
Duralumin!
What the devil have you done?
Why should my daughter... I
mean, my son be executed?
This is the death
warrant with your seal!
His Highness has broken 30 idols!
Oh, my Sapphire! What have you done?
Why? Why did you
want to break our laws...
...and commit such a sacrilege?
Sapphire!
Forgive me, mother! I
didn't want to make you cry!
Damn it! If only I
could untie myself!
Sire, we will soon begin
the execution of the verdict.
- Such a good boy!
- Sapphire!
Sapphire! Sapphire, no! Sapphire!
Stop!
The law forbids you to go!
Nylon, let me pass,
please!
You cannot go up the tower!
Forgive me, Your Highness, I am
forced to do my duty.
Do you really want to hang him, dad?
You know, I feel very sorry for him.
Shut up! Watch, instead,
and learn how it's done.
Tink, are you glad
that we will go to Heaven together?
Come on, my son!
Pass me the rope!
- Please, Prince, escape!
- Thank you!
Prince Sapphire has freed himself!
Your Majesty, Prince Sapphire
has rebelled!
- Damn it!
- Did you hear?
- Our son Sapphire!
- It's true, our son...
- He will not escape his punishment!
- But I...!
Prince Sapphire, now,
is an outlaw,
so shoot arrows at him
and kill him!
No, Duralumin! Not this!
What do you think? That the life
of the Prince is more important...
...or the existence of Silverland?
Hurry, Sapphire!
Too late!
I can't make it anymore!
Prince, it is useless for you
to rebel against your destiny!
Your parents will not be left
with a good memory of you...
..if you perish as a rebel!
You want to see me
dead, Baron Nylon, huh?
But I won't let you win,
this time!
Look!
- Let's help Prince Sapphire!
- Let's help him!
Who is that scoundrel who dares
to destroy the last sacred idols?
Courage! Courage, Sapphire!
Farewell, my dear parents..!
Let's go help Sapphire!
Let's do as he does!
We absolutely must do
something! Let's help him!
Let's help Sapphire!
We must help him!
What's happening? Speak!
A crowd of women is
rushing at the sacred idols.
They say they want
to help the Prince!
I cannot allow
such a thing!
Go home, wife,
or I'll lose my job!
Do you think just because you earn a few measly coins, you can order me around?
But dear...!
Good job! You did well!
Let's break everything!
Women, please, stop!
Get your hands off me! That'll
teach you to touch a lady!
Damned breed of savages!
Stop the execution and
arrest these frantic women!
The women have proven
to be smarter than the men!
How can stones
drive away evil spirits?
Now that we are imprisoned,
we don't care at all..
..about foolish traditions!
We will regain our freedom!
Now that we are already
condemned, we all remain happy!
And with the fallen
idols superstition will fall!
A lesson must be taught here!
One of them will go to the gallows!
What do you say? Am I doing the right thing?
It's Mephisto!
- Hail, Mephisto!
- Duralumin!
You tried to kill Sapphire
without my permission.
I will only forgive you if you get me
her heart! Understood?
Forgive me, Mephisto!
All right, I will give it to you!
I cannot get close to Sapphire
because she always has that angel
in the way!
Make sure he is left alone!
All right, as you wish!
I will only let him out of the cell.
That's fine.
Well? What's new now?
Follow me, Your Highness.
The King wishes to see you.
- All right, take me to him.
- What do you think he wants to tell you, Sapphire?
It could be a good sign:
maybe he will grant me a pardon.
But then it's a trap!
This time you won't succeed
in escaping, Prince.
You will end up being hanged,
so resign yourself...
..and put down that sword!
Then come and get it,
if you can!
Go get him and try
to make up for it, after that fiasco of yours!
Halt!
I'm sorry, Prince,
but I must complete my
work, so let yourself be captured!
You don't want to?
Then it will be worse for you!
What... What a strange wind!
It's lifting me up!
I did it! This must be
the devil's work!
What kind of cloud is this?!
I get it, it's Mephisto!
Perhaps the time has come
to step out.
All too easy!
It is useless for you to
try to escape your destiny!
You won't get away
with it, Prince Sapphire!
Finally I will be able to
tear out your male heart!
It's fantastic!
You won't dare fight
Mephisto! You wouldn't make it!
Mephisto is hurling
the stone idols at me!
I surrender, Mephisto!
I see with pleasure that you
have come to wiser counsel!
Even if I take one heart from
you, you will still have the other!
Damn, the chain is stiff!
Take this!
Damn it!
It's over for you!
You cannot make me succumb!
- Stop fighting me!
- Never!
- Even if you're right...
- Now...
...stare at me.
Go back to hell
and don't make me angry!
Otherwise I will make you suffer
the most excruciating pain...
...that you have ever felt!
Understood?
All right,
but don't get any closer than that!
Get lost right now or I'll jump on you
and make you feel my hands!
Okay, I'm leaving!
But stay where you are!
I feel my body weakening!
Sapphire is safe!
Yeah, he's safe!
I'm glad you're safe!
But why are you crying?
I'm sorry
for causing you so much pain!
Mom, I won't cause you any more!
But I'm glad
I destroyed the idols.
- What is he here to do?
- What does he want?
Well! You've had enough fun,
haven't you?
Well, you see, we...
You must have realized that Mephisto
is the only evil spirit,
So you must be convinced that
those idols were completely useless!
Isn't it funny to have believed for
so long in the power of those stones?
And you must also have seen that the
devil cannot be defeated with stones!
Doesn't this make you laugh, Grand Duke?
I wish I could sink into
the ground! Like this!
It takes very little to
defeat superstitions!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP